Guide to the Romeyn Berry family papers, 1636-1960.
Berry, Romeyn family papers,
- Series I. Romeyn Berry
  - Subseries Ig. Cornell Material
    - The Misfit Man presented by The Cornell Masque, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - John F. Moakley biography and notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Rowalnd versus Hammond typewriter notes and correspondence, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - The College Biddy, 1900-1910 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Cornelliana, 1900-1910 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Includes Lehi Valley Railroad ticket, Spring Day Big Double Show (1908), receipts for the Widow, Ass. Managers Banquet ribbon, and folded scrapbook page with invitations and lecture notes
    - Is Cornell Unique? Draft by J. L. Zwingle, with letter, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Student scrapbook, 1899-1906 (Box 10)
      Scrapbook includes: photographs of people and athletic events (baseball, boating, and football), clippings, invitations and programs, ticket stubs, football programs, Beta Theta Pi material, Athletic Association documents and programs, trade stakes, "The Widow" documents and programs, track documents, ribbons and awards, 1903 red beanie, and a Macaronigram.
    - Lyceum Theater accounts, 1893-1923 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Series II. Harriet V.V. Berry and Elizabeth Berry
  - Harriet Berry correspondence and documents, 1891-1918 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    Includes correspondence about cemetery upkeep
  - Agreement settling the estate of Harriet V.V. Berry and the final settlement of the account of Romeyn Berry, as executor of the will of Elisabeth W. Berry, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Elizabeth Berry correspondence and will, 1909-1923 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Elizabeth Berry estate documents, 1921-1928 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Series III. Berry/Gould Family Material
  - Geneology and family history, Undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Martin van Buren death claim report and biography (copy), Undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    Romeyn Berry's grandfather preached at Van Buren's funeral surface
  - Various pamphlets on gardening and architecture and other topics, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 24-26)
    Includes The Architectural Record, The Lantern Westover School Magazine, Brookgreen Gardens History, A Century of Growth, and more
  - 5 pp. of biographical data concerning Warner ("Butch") Berry's first three years of life, Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "History of the Village of Brookton" (dictated by Cantine Lounsbery, July 11, 1907, 2 pp. typescript), 1907-07-11 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Geological Survey Map of New York - Ithaca Quadrangle, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Berry Family Tree, Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Hand drawn calling cards/place settings, Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Rutgers College commencement program, 1974-07-17 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Various documents, Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Includes hand drawn map from Ithaca to Pittsfield,
  - Daily journal, writer unknown, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - A small notebook partially filled with notes on animal diseases and notations "Stock Book" (owner unknown)., 1939 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Volumes III and V of daily farm diary, possibly written by Romeyn Berry, 1943-1950 (Box 10)
  - Ruth Berry Sunday school handouts, Undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Hannah Gould Garden Diary, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Includes piece of wood with drawing of Harriet and Romeyn
  - Trust document, letter to Miss Berry, 1928-1931 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Desk diary, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    Romeyn or Hester Berry's
  - Mounted image of saint, Undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Indenture - Yorkshire, 1636 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Indenture - Lancashire, England, 1691 (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Series IV. Hester Bancroft Berry and Wilder Bancroft
  - Bancroft family correspondence, 1881-1941 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    Letters to George and John C. Bancroft (the letter to George appears to be from John, but the last page is missing) of May 11 and 12, 1881, concerning the will of Abisha Larned of Oxford, Mass., a copy of the will, and other relevant information; a letter from Peter Cantine (location?) to Charles F. Mulks (Ithaca), Jan. 15, 1895, re: Cantine's family genealogy, which Mulks had apparently requested, and in turn requesting information from Mulks in order to "prove" the will of a Samuel W. Ransom; two letters to Wilder D. Bancroft from Mark A. DeWolfe Howe (July 15 and Dec. 14, 1904); fifteen letters (Nov. 20-23, 1906) from various British scientists to Sir William Ramsay, regarding Wilder Bancroft's suggestion that the Journal of Physical Chemistry be published in England; letters to Hester Bancroft in Europe (ca. 1926), including a letter from Morris Bishop (Feb. 18, 1926); and other letters to Hester and Romeyn Berry, pertaining to Hester Berry's sculptures, the launching of the U.S.S. Bancroft, publication of Romeyn's work by Putnam's, and other topics. Also a printed Christmas card from Sir Wilfred and Lady Grenfell (undated.) and a Christmas card from a drawing by Hester Berry (May 11, 1881-Mar. 31, 1953).
  - Wilder Bancroft will, 1939-12-04 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Inventory of Wilder Bancroft estate items, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Art objects displayed and stored at the Worcester Art Museum, Worcester, Mass. Acc. Nos. given by each item.
  - Newspaper clippings, 1923-1955 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Clippings (25 items) from many newspapers relating to Professor Wilder Bancroft's experiments in rain-making (1923); a page from the Ithaca Journal about early explorers and travellers in Tompkins County (Jan. 26, 1955); and other items.
  - "Stoneposts - Stock on Hand," a book kept by Hester Berry - egg, cream sales, etc., 1936-1938 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - A European travel diary kept by Katherine Bott (later Mrs. Wilder Bancroft) in the summer, 1880 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - "Greenhouse Diary," a small partially filled notebook kept by Hester Berry, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Hester Bancroft passport, receipts, 1899 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Mrs. Romeyn Berry name plate, Undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence pertaining to family estates, 1952-1954 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Poems by Hester Bancroft, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Poems by Hester Bancroft, 1914-1916 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - A notebook of poems written about or during World War I compiled by Hester Bancroft., 1914-1919 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Series V. Olive Nutting Berry and Nutting Family
  - Lee Nutting civil war record and tax documents, 1908-1927 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Olive Berry indenture, 1919-08-18 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Olive Nutting Berry scrapbook, 1902-1912 (Box 8)
    Includes invitations to social functions at Cornell University and elsewhere, programs, postcards, photographs; Wells College material including a manual, constitution and by-laws and two copies of the Wells College Chronicle, correspondence, poetry from Romeyn Berry to Olive, formal announcement of the their wedding, calling cards, a copy of the Cornell Alumni News and photographs of fraternity parties at Cornell.
  - Printed items removed from Olive Nutting Berry scrapbook, 1903-1909 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Olive Nutting Berry scrapbook items, loose, 1902-1912 (Box 8, Folder 2-4)
  - Olive Lee Berry memorial from Garden Club of Ithaca, Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Olive Lee Berry card and stationary plate receipts, Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Article from the Ithaca Daily News on Cornell Crew, with R.W. Nutting, 1904-07-29 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Series VI. Photographs and artwork
  - Photographs of Romeyn Berry, Undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Photographs of Romeyn Berry (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Photographs of Romeyn, Hester, Butch, and the farm, Undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Child with dogs, Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of Hester in costume, Undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified photographs, Undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of Gettysburg, Pennsylvania, 1954-04-17 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Portrait photograph of Ezra Cornell, gift of C.H. Blair 1936, Undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Glossy print of George Bancroft portrait, Undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Negatives, Undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Reproductions of pen and ink drawings (etchings?) by Daubigny, Corot, Rousseau, and other artists, Undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Includes many unidentified photographs, large photograph of the Cornell Crew, and a class of 1907 reunion photograph
  - Scrapbook of photographs of South Ireland, Undated (Box 7)
  - Reproductions of pen and ink drawings (etchings?) by Daubigny, Corot, Rousseau, and other artists, Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of sculptures by Hester Bancroft Berry, 1928-1936 (Box 9, Folder 16-17)
  - Hester Bancroft's photo album, Undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Hester Bancroft's photo album, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - List of individuals in military photographs, Undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
    Not matched with any photographs in the collections
  - Water colors, washes, oils, etchings, and pencil and charcoal drawings, many of foreign scenes, likely by Hester Bancroft, 1920-1940 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Water colors, washes, oils, etchings, and pencil and charcoal drawings, many of foreign scenes, likely by Hester Bancroft, 1920-1940 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Watercolor picture, Undated (Box MS, Folder 1)
  - 3 oversized comic photographs of "boxers," including Berry and Robert Elias Treman, Undated (Box MS, Folder 1)
  - Watercolors and a print of a bird, 1880-1900 (Mapcase-folder 2)
- Series VII. Medals, Ribbons, and objects
  - University of Pennsylvania tenth annual intercollegiate and interscholastic relay race meeting, 1904; MU-2778 (Box 12)
  - Marshal, International track and field meet, Travers Island, 1929-07-20; MU-2779 (Box 12)
  - Long Island Interscholastic Athletic League, pole vault, 1900; MU-2780 (Box 12)
  - Inspector, New York Athletic Club, 1911-02-18; MU-2804 (Box 12)
  - Inspector, New York Athletic Club, 1914-02-11; MU-2781 (Box 12)
  - Pole vault medal, 1899; MU-2810 (Box 12)
  - Run High Jump medal, 1900; MU-2782 (Box 12)
  - HHSAA hammer throw, Undated; MU-2783 (Box 12)
  - Judge at Finish, Oxford-Cambridge vs. Harvard-Yale track meet, Undated; MU-2784 (Box 12)
  - Field Judge FHAC, Undated; MU-2785 (Box 12)
  - Official, IAAC, Undated; MU-2786 (Box 12)
  - Field Judge, unlabelled medal with winged foot, Undated; MU-2787 (Box 12)
  - Inspector, Columbia University, 1912-02-17; MU-2788 (Box 12)
  - Judge at Finish, Dartmouth College, University of Pennsylvania, Yale University track meet, 1925-05-02; MU-2789 (Box 12)
  - International Collegiate Athletic Association 187th annual convention, 1923-12-28; MU-2790 (Box 12)
  - 17th annual convention National Collegiate Athletic Association, 1922-12-28; MU-2791 (Box 12)
  - Yale vs. Notre Dame, 1923-05-11; MU-2792 (Box 12)
  - Official, Princeton-Yale Track AA, Undated; MU-2793 (Box 12)
  - Inspector, Harvard-Yale Athletic Association, 1911-05-13; MU-2794 (Box 12)
  - Field judge, Harvard-Yale Athletic Association, 1915-05-15; MU-2838 (Box 13)
  - Track judge, 25th annual relay race carnival, University of Pennsylvania, 1919; MU-2798 (Box 12)
  - Track judge, 30th annual relay race carnival, University of Pennsylvania, 1924; MU-2795 (Box 12)
  - Track judge, 31st annual relay race carnival, University of Pennsylvania, 1925; MU-2796 (Box 12)
  - Track judge, 32nd annual relay race carnival, University of Pennsylvania, 1926; MU-2819 (Box 12)
  - Track judge, 33rd annual relay race carnival, University of Pennsylvania, 1927; MU-2797 (Box 12)
  - Judge, ICAAAA, Undated; MU-2799 (Box 12)
  - Field judge, Senior and Junior AAU national championships, 1916-09-08; MU-2800 (Box 12)
  - Inspector, Columbia University indoor meet, 1909; MU-2801 (Box 12)
  - Inspector, 10th annual indoor relay carnival, Columbia University, 1910-03-12; MU-2802 (Box 12)
  - Inspector, 1913-02-15; MU-2803 (Box 12)
    Ribbon only, medal missing
  - Sigma Alpha Epsilon pin, Undated; MU-2805 (Box 12)
  - US military pins, Undated; MU-2806-2807 (Box 12)
  - Theodore Roosevelt for President political button, Undated; MU-2808 (Box 12)
  - Dunston pin, 1900-1920; MU-2809 (Box 12)
    Small monk's head pin from Cornell's Dunston society
  - Director of field, ICAAAA 41st annual field meet, 1916-05-27; MU-2811 (Box 12)
  - Chief inspector, 8th annual cross country championships of the ICAAAA, 1915-11-20; MU-2812 (Box 12)
  - Clerk of course, 8th annual cross country championships, ICAAAA, 1915-11-20; MU-2827 (Box 12)
  - Chief inspector, 9th annual cross country championships of the ICAAAA, 1916-11-25; MU-2828 (Box 12)
  - Inspector, 10th annual cross country championships of the ICAAAA, 1917-11-24; MU-2829 (Box 12)
  - Judge at Finish, 42nd annual track and field championships, ICAAAA, 1918-05-31; MU-2830 (Box 12)
  - Judge at Finish, 43rd annual track and field championships, ICAAAA, 1919-05-30; MU-2813 (Box 12)
  - Judge at Finish, 44th annual track and field championships, ICAAAA, 1920-05-28; MU-2814 (Box 12)
  - Judge at Finish, 45th annual track and field championships, ICAAAA, 1921-05-27; MU-2815 (Box 12)
  - Judge at Finish, 4th annual indoor championship, ICAAAA, 1925-03-07; MU-2816 (Box 12)
  - Judge at Finish, 49th annual track and field championships, ICAAAA, 1925-05-29; MU-2817 (Box 12)
  - Inspector, ICAAAA Cross County Run, Columbia, 1913-11-22; MU-2818 (Box 12)
  - Inspector, 5th annual cross country run, ICAAAA, 1912; MU-2820 (Box 12)
  - Advisory committee, 1st annual cross country run, ICAAAA, 1908-11-21; MU-2821 (Box 12)
  - Inspector, 3rd annual cross country run, ICAAAA, 1910-11-12; MU-2822 (Box 12)
  - Inspector, 35th annual field meet, ICAAAA, 1910; MU-2823 (Box 12)
  - Advisory committee, 36th annual field meet, ICAAAA, 1911-05-26; MU-2824 (Box 12)
  - Inspector, 37th annual field meet, ICAAAA, 1912-05-31; MU-2825 (Box 12)
  - Advisory committee, 38th annual field meet, ICAAAA, 1913-05-30; MU-2826 (Box 12)
  - Advisory committee, ICAAAA medal, 1912; MU-2831 (Box 13)
    Engraved
  - Advisory committee, ICAAAA medal, 1913; MU-2832 (Box 13)
  - Advisory committee, ICAAAA medal, 1914; MU-2833 (Box 13)
  - Advisory committee/treasurer, ICAAAA, 1907-1908; MU-2839 (Box 13)
  - Phi Beta Kappa medal, Undated; MU-2834 (Box 13)
    Back engrave, "W.B.Berry, Dec. 5th 1776"
  - Columbia athletic medal, Undated; MU-2835 (Box 13)
  - NY Giants Worlds Championship charm, 1921; MU-2836 (Box 13)
    Back engraved, "1922, 349 Romeyn Berry"
  - Delta Kappa Epsilon medal, Undated; MU-2837 (Box 13)
    Back engraved, "R.M.L."
  - Cornell Varsity Crew, R.W.Nutting, Undated; MU-2840 (Box 13)
  - Carved bone bobbin and crotchet hook, Undated; MU-2841 (Box 13)
  - The Romeyn fly, Undated; MU-2842 (Box 13)
    Fly-fishing lure on card, describing the "Romeyn" fly
  - Printer's block image of Romeyn Berry, Undated; MU-2843 (Box 13)
  - Romeyn Berry's stopwatch, 1921; MU-2844 (Box 13)
    Back engraved, "To Romeyn Berry, with best wishes, from Gustavus T. Kirby"